<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
  <info>
    <name>Druid2PointOh</name>
    <description>The Circle of Verdant</description>
    <author url="http://dnd.wizards.com/products/tabletop-games/rpg-products/xanathars-guide-everything">Xanathar’s Guide to Everything</author>
    <update version="0.0.4">
      <file name="druid-2pointOh.xml" url="https://github.com/Emrryz/Aurora/blob/main/druid-2PointOh.xml" />
    </update>
  </info>
  <element name="Circle of the Verdant" type="Archetype" source="Xanathar’s Guide to Everything" id="ID_WOTC_XGTE_ARCHETYPE_CIRCLE_OF_VERDANT">
    <supports>Druid Circle</supports>
    <description>
      <p>Druids of the Verdant Circle are most at peace among the green wilds, tending to wildflower blooms, sacred groves, vine-bound rainforests and even seagrass plains dancing on he ocean floor. These druids fight fiercly to defend this life upon which all other life depends, and are protected and nutured in return</p>
      <div element="ID_WOTC_XGTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_VERDANT_GROVE_PROTECTOR" />
      <div element="ID_WOTC_XGTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_VERDANT_FORM" />
      <div element="ID_WOTC_XGTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_LIFEBLOOM" />
      <div element="ID_WOTC_XGTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DREAMS_WALKER_IN_DREAMS" />
    </description>
    <sheet display="false" />
    <rules>
      <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_XGTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_VERDANT_GROVE_PROTECTOR" level="2" />
      <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_XGTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_VERDANT_FORM" level="2" />
      <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_XGTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_LIFEBLOOM" level="10" />
      <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_XGTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DREAMS_WALKER_IN_DREAMS" level="14" />
    </rules>
  </element>
  <element name="Grove Protector" type="Archetype Feature" source="Xanathar’s Guide to Everything" id="ID_WOTC_XGTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_VERDANT_GROVE_PROTECTOR">
		<description>
			<p>Upon joining the Circle of the Verdant at 2nd level, you gain the ability to charge seeds or spores with sentience and purposeful life, growing and awakened plant friend that joins
			you on your adventure and defends you and your friends. You can spend 8 hours tending to a seed, bud or spore, rooting it in a sacred soil, feeding it with enchanted waters, or bathing
			it in blessed light. At the end of 8 hours, your friend sprouts to full size, in a size from small to large (your choice).
			Choose a friend from among the following types: living tree, blood rose, vine creeper, or myconid, each with unique statistics. See this creature's game statistics below. You may also choose
			up to two variant features for your friend, listed below, and an additional variant feature each at 11th and 17th level.
			Your plant friend obeys your commands (no action required by you) and takes its turn on your initiative. Your plant friend can also be commanded to melf with you or another friendly creature
			, as though mounted, its bark, its roots or vines can mesh seamlessly with flesh, clothing and armor. While in this combined form the plant friend can use its reaction to intercept up to half of the damage intended for its symbiote.
			If your friends body is destroyed, it leaves Behind a seed, bud or spore and regrows with 1 hit point over 1 hour. You can choose a different plant form for your friend, tranferring its consciousness
			 with ease. As an action, you can accelerate this proccess of regrowth, using one use of your Wild Shape to instantly revive your friend with 1 hit point.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>You can summon a plant companion over 8 hours (living tree, blood rose, vine creeper, or myconid).</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>

  <element name="Verdant Form" type="Archetype Feature" source="Xanathar’s Guide to Everything" id="ID_WOTC_XGTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_VERDANT_FORM">
    <description>
      <p>Your familiarity with verdant life grants you the ability to take on their forms and attune to them through magic. At 2nd level, plants are considered beasts for the purpose of all your druid spells and features. Moreover, as an action, you can expend one use of your
	  Wild Shape to surge your plant friend with life, restoring a number of hitpoints equal to 3x your druid level, divided between your plant friend and its symbiote as your choose. As part of the same action you can shift the form of your plant friend to another type you can growing
	  , this new form lasting as long as your own Wild Shape</p>
    </description>
    <sheet>
      <description>as an action, spend 1 Wild Shape charge to heal your plant friend/symbiote 3x your druid level, devided between as you wish.</description>
    </sheet>
  </element>
  
  <element name="Lifebloom" type="Archetype Feature" source="Xanathar’s Guide to Everything" id="ID_WOTC_XGTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_LIFEBLOOM">
    <description>
      <p>Starting at 6th level, you gain the ability to effortlessly call nature's splendor around you. As a bonus action you can activate or quiet your verdant power. Wherever you go, plants sprout and bloom, and small creatures friendly to you emerge to follow.</p>
      <p class="indent">When you move, greenery traces your steps, remaining until the beginning of your next turn. In addition, you emanate a perpetual aura of blooming life around you in a 15-foot radius.</p>
	  <p class="indent">While you remain still, this aura grows by an additional 5 feet per turn, up to a maximum of 120 feet, retracting when you move once more. </p>
	  <p class="indent">Whenever you cast a druid spell, the aura also erupts under any creatures, objects or areas you target, lasting until the end of your next turn. Choose from one pf the following effects for your lifebloom aura whenerver you finish a long rest.</p>
	  <p class="indent"><b>Cradle of Life.</b> The life within your aura teems with vitality, sprouting berries and edible flowers, and overflowing with honey and sweet saps. It grows enough food to nourish one medium sized creature each day, and purifies enough water for two to drink.
	   In addition, any creature of your choice that stands in your aura recieves additional healing equal to your Wisdom modifier (minimum of 1) whenever theu regain hit points in any way.</p>
	   <p class = "indent"><b>Whispering wilds.</b> Any tangible creatures in your aura are revealed as the overgrown foliage and the bounty of creatures within, alert all to their presence. In addition, when a creature enters or leaves your aura for the first time on a turn, they must expend 5 feet of movement
	   and take slashing, piercing or poison damage (your choice) equal ro your Wisdom modifier (minimum of 1). You can exclude cretaures of your choice from 1 of these effects.</p>
    </description>
    <sheet action="Bonus Action" usage="{{wisdom:modifier}}/Long Rest">
      <description>Teleport up to 60ft.
	  Alternatively, as an action you teleport a willing creature you touch up to 30ft.</description>
    </sheet>
  </element>
  <element name="Walker in Dreams" type="Archetype Feature" source="Xanathar’s Guide to Everything" id="ID_WOTC_XGTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DREAMS_WALKER_IN_DREAMS">
    <description>
      <p>At 14th level, the magic of the Feywild grants you the ability to travel mentally or physically through dreamlands.</p>
      <p class="indent">When you finish a short rest, you can cast one of the following spells, without expending a spell slot or requiring material components: dream (with you as the messenger), scrying, or teleportation circle.</p>
      <p class="indent">This use of teleportation circle is special. Rather than opening a portal to a permanent teleportation circle, it opens a portal to the last location where you finished a long rest on your current plane of existence. If you haven't taken a long rest on your current plane, the spell fails but isn’t wasted.</p>
      <p class="indent">Once you use this feature, you can’t use it again until you finish a long rest.</p>
    </description>
    <sheet usage="1/Long Rest">
      <description>When finishing a short rest, cast Dream, Scrying, or Teleportation Circle without using a spell slot, or material component. This use of teleportation circle is special. Rather than opening a portal to a permanent teleportation circle, it opens a portal to the last location where you finished a long rest on your current plane of existence.</description>
    </sheet>
  </element>
</elements>